

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER 136 Belvedere Street, San Francisco jacob.sf.us@gmail.com (415) 766-1867 https://linkedin.com/in/jacobswartz

In-depth understanding of software development fundamentals. Specialized experience in eCommerce and SEO & SEM. Intuition for detail and visual aesthetics. Highly self-motivated – capable of working independently as well as being a key asset to any team, with a passion to share knowledge and improve & expand skillsets.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Development

- Object-oriented PHP
- JavaScript
- Bash
- Node.js/Vue.js/Webpack
- HTML5/CSS3/Sass
- SVN/git
- MySQL
- Apache
- xcache/memcache
- SEO/SEM

Testing

- PHPUnit/xdebug
- JMeter/Apache Bench
- KCachegrind
- New Relic/Yslow/PageSpeed

Collaboration

- IRC
- Basecamp
- Trac
- JIRA

Virtualization

- VirtualBox/VMWare
- Vagrant/PuPHPet
- Amazon Web Services
- Docker

0S

- Debian Linux
- MacOS
- · Windows 7, 10

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Consultant

The Internet; Jan 2015 - Present

- Develop, maintain, and manage sites and custom features for clients
- Install and configure versioning, web, and mailservers
- · Utilize APIs to quickly import product metadata, reducing ingestion time
- Generate tailored reports from cart platforms for e-commerce clients
- · Create email campaigns using MailChimp and Campaign Monitor

Lead Creative Consultant at Bluestone Creative Cincinnati, Ohio; Mar 2014 - Sep 2014

- Implemented and configured hardware for in-house web, storage, and FTP servers
- Set up tools for project tracking, task management, and time logging
- Created website boilerplates for various categories of clients

Software Engineer at Ask.com Oakland, California; Oct 2012 - Jul 2013

- Worked on an agile development team responsible for 3+ million unique articles and Q&A pairs
- Repaired sites affected by Google's search algorithm "Panda", resuming AdSense revenue
- Led team to use more efficient processes in order to more rapidly create, edit, and share mockups and one-offs
- Migrated top revenue earning sites to dotCMS under strict deadlines

Continued on next page...



SOFTWARE DEVELOPER SOFTWARE DEVELOPER
136 Belvedere Street, San Francisco
jacob.sf.us@gmail.com (415) 766-1867 https://linkedin.com/in/jacobswartz

EXPERIENCE CONT'D

Web Developer at FontShop International, Inc San Francisco, California; Oct 2008 – July 2012

- Created a dynamic, responsive eCommerce experience using HTML5, CSS3 + Sass, and JavaScript
- Optimized pages to decrease load time and increase SEO ranking
- Developed font rendering tool for sampling over 100,000 typefaces
- Implemented sitewide templating and internationalization supporting 4 languages
- Migrated from cumbersome images and Flash hacks to webfonts with TypeKit
- · Worked with payment processing systems: CyberSource, Ogone
- Maintained WordPress blog extended with custom features
- Helped organize and run TYPO one of Europe's most successful design conferences for its U.S. premiere at Yerba Buena Center for the Arts

Web Developer at Fish Flirt Marketing Dayton, Ohio; May 2007 - Oct 2008

- Developed and maintained websites for clients using the LAMP stack. W3C compliant HTML4, CSS2, and JavaScript
- Installed, configured, and managed SVN, web, and mail servers

EDUCATION

Sinclair Community College Dayton, Ohio; Apr 2007 - Oct 2008 • AAS, Computer Information Systems

REFERENCES Available on request